（信(しん)）痛(いて)えな こらぁ！
That hurt, dammit!
（壁(へき)）と… 届いた！
He-He made it!
（竭氏(けつし)）うん？
Kill that little monkey!
（竭氏）あの小猿を殺せ！
（信）ああ 来た来た
Ooh, here they come.
This is also my battle to avenge Piao, so I'm not going easy on you.
漂(ひょう)の弔い合戦 兼ねてっから
容赦しねえぞ
ハアーッ！
Ancient China.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望が解放されていた
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars, lasting a monumentally long 500 years, erupted all across China.
激烈なる戦争と戦乱の嵐が―
500年という
途方もなく長きにわたって―
中国全土に吹き荒れていた
欲望 快楽 苦痛 恐怖…
Desire, pleasure, pain, fear.
過酷で絶望に満ちた その世界には
竜がいたに違いない
With such relentless despair filling the world, it was as though a dragon had invaded.
A dragon called the "era".
“時代”という名の竜が
And as if burned by the flames of a dragon,
そして
竜の炎に焼かれるかのように―
over one hundred states were destroyed, one by one, until only seven were left standing.
100を超える国は 次々と滅び
今や ７国に淘汰(とうた)されていた
Yan, Qi, Zhao, Wei, Han, Chu...
燕(えん) 斉(せい) 趙(ちょう) 魏(ぎ) 韓(かん) 楚(そ)…
そして 秦(しん)である
and Qin.
The seven great powers, in order to devour each other,
７つの大国は おのおのが
おのおのを食らい尽くすように―
took up their swords of desire and continuously pierced the throats of enemy states.
欲望の剣を 敵国の喉元に向かって
突き立て続けた
世にいう春秋戦国時代である
The world knew it as the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
そして今 西の果て 秦の国から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
大きな歴史の風が
吹き荒れようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を走り抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
KoolKidsK
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Fierce Fighting Begins
Protect the gate!
（門番）門を守れ！ ンンッ！
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
They're breaking through the Zhugui Gate!
（江(こう)）朱亀(しゅき)の門が破られまする！
（竭氏）おのれ！
Bastards...
（戦士たち）ヤーッ！
（信）じゃ～ん！
Ta-da.
（壁）よくやったぞ 信！
（信）余裕
Well done, Xin!
Piece of cake.
Go! Go!
出せ！ 出せ！
（政(せい)）
馬車を狙え！ ヤツが竭丞相(じょうしょう)だ
Target the coach! That's Chancellor Jie!
（楊端和(ようたんわ)たち）ハッ…
竭丞相って…
大将首の片っぽじゃねえか！
Chancellor Jie...?
That's one of the frickin' enemy generals!
（信）早く言えっつうの！
Tell us that stuff sooner!
What is it, Lankai?
（成蟜(せいきょう)）どうした？ ランカイ
Faster! Faster!
（江）飛ばせ 飛ばせ！
Drat! They're catching up!
いかん 追いつかれる！
（竭氏）ンッ！
（江）ウワッ…
ンンッ！
（江）な… 何をなされるのです…
Wh-What're you doing?!
（戦士たち）ウワッ…
（信）ウワッ！
何だ？ あの野郎
自分の部下を投げやがったぞ！
What's with that bastard?!
He threw his own freaking subordinate!
That's terrible!
（貂(てん)）
ひどいな… あのおっさん 最低だ
That old man is an ass!
竭丞相だけじゃない
It's not just Chancellor Jie...
All the ministers serving in the royal palace apart from Lord are like that!
王宮に はべる大臣は
殿以外 あんなヤツばかりだ
（戦士）ンッ！
（兵士）ウワッ…
（信）ゲゲッ！ あいつら 馬を…
先 越されちまう！
Those guys've got a horse...!
They're gonna overtake him first!
What?!
なにぃ？
It looks like they're not actually gonna make it.
意外と あっけなかったな
We've lured Jie Shi this far!
ここまで竭氏をおびき出した―
大王と殿の作戦勝ちだ！
His Highness and Lord's strategy was a success!
It's frustrating that they're able to protect one of the enemy generals, but that old man is done for!
大将首１つ取られるのは悔しいが
あのおっさん もうおしまいだぜ
Stop!
止まれ！
（戦士たち）ウワッ！
肆氏(しし)！
Shi Shi!
Th-They've got more people than they had before...
（貂）さ… さっきより数が多いし
それに なんか怖い
And they're kinda scarier.
でかしたぞ 肆氏
（肆氏）はっ！
Well done, Shi Shi.
Yes, sir!
じゃが 貴様… ヤツらが欺くと
どうして見破った？
But Shi Shi, you dog... How did you see through their deception?
彼らが都に現れたとき―
When they appeared at the capital...
I saw someone among them hiding something glimmering underneath their straw coat.
蓑笠(みのかさ)の下に光り物を
着込んでいる者が―
交じっておりました
恐らく あれは甲冑(かっちゅう)
It's likely... that was armor.
There are Flatland People among them?
平地の者が交じっていると？
It is probable that the reason the Mountain People descended from the mountains on this occasion...
こたびの山の民の下山は
平地の何者かが促したものでしょう
was that someone from the flatlands prompted them to.
However, there are not many people who could cause the Mountain People to act.
しかし 山の民を動かせるような
平地の者など そうは いますまい
まさか…
You don't mean...?!
He's keeping his head down.
首が挙がっておりませぬ
間違いないでしょう
But I'm sure of it.
Show yourself!
姿を現しなされい 大王 嬴政(えいせい)！
King Ying Zheng!
肆氏が率いている兵は
歴戦の猛者たちだ
The soldiers Shi Shi is leading are stalwarts with long military services.
The difference in numbers is becoming apparent.
この人数の差は まともに出るぞ
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）いかにも
Indeed.
Send off the right flank with Bi.
（政）壁より右を離せ
（昌文君）はっ！
Yes, my king!
What's wrong?!
（肆氏）どうされました？
（昌文君）壁！
（壁）はっ！
Bi!
Sir?
We know you're there!
そこに おられるのは
分かっておりますぞ！
Do not pretend to hide!
お隠れあそばされるな！
では…
Yes, sir.
（昌文君）武運を祈る
（壁）はっ！
I pray for your fortune in battle.
Yes.
Come on out! King Ying Zheng!
（肆氏）出てこられよ 大王 嬴政！
嬴政！
Ying Zheng!
Have you enjoyed your brief moment of glory, Chancellor Shi?
（政）つかの間の栄華を
楽しんだか？ 竭丞相
Has it been enough?
もう十分だな？
Showing himself without any guards... foolish.
護衛もなく現れるとは… 愚かな
What's he doing?!
何やってんだ！
あいつ 狙い撃ちされるぞ
They're gonna shoot him!
It's all right.
（壁）大丈夫だ
Their arrows won't reach from this distance.
この距離なら 矢は届かん
（信）壁のあんちゃん…
Brother Bi.
Bajiou, we're going to form the right flank into a separate squadron.
（壁）バジオウ
ここから右を別動隊とする
Come with me.
私に ついてきてくれ
（バジオウ）分かった
Understood.
Separate squadron?
別動隊？
（壁）そうだ　行くぞ 信
That's right. Let's go, Xin.
ちょっと待て！
Hold on a sec!
Those guys don't have the same feel to them as the guards from before!
あの連中は
さっきの衛兵とは気配が違う
If me and Captain ain't here, Zheng's gonna be in trouble!
俺や隊長がいないと
政のヤツが危ないぜ！
This is the strategy.
これは作戦だ
（壁）王が
敵を引き付けておられるうちに―
While the king draws the enemy's attention,
we enter the inner palace and attack Chengjiao!
我らで 本殿にいる成蟜を討つ！
（王騎(おうき)）ほう…
けなげな王ではありませんか
What a courageous king.
（王騎）面白くなってきましたねえ
Things have gotten quite interesting...
Forward!
（魏興(ぎこう)）進めー！
刃向かう者どもを
蜂の巣にし
The enemy has entered the bee's nest!
Weixing
Knock off the king's head!
大王の首を
たたき落とせ！
（竭氏）うん？
あやつら 回廊に向かっておるぞ
Those ones are heading for the corridor!
There may be few of them, but would it not be dangerous to ignore the inside of the building?
少数とはいえ―
建物の中に見失うのは
やっかいではないか？
No need to worry.
ご心配なく
Down that corridor... is Zuoci!
回廊には 左慈(さじ)がおります
（信）オッ… いっけえ タジフ！
Do it, Tajif!
痛え！ ダハッ…
（貂）やった！
Ow!
He did it!
Okay, let's head in.
よし 入るぞ！
（信）アア…
（壁）大丈夫だ
It'll be all right.
王には 殿や山の民が ついている
The king has Lord and the Mountain People with him.
We have our own duty to fulfill.
私たちは
私たちの役目を果たすんだ
分かってるよ
I know.
Let's get a move on, Brother Bi!
（信）
モタモタすんな 壁のあんちゃん！
Prepare to fire!
射撃用意！
（昌文君）魏興配下の兵は
他国も恐れる弓の名手ぞろい
The soldiers under Weixing are even feared by other states as expert archers.
射程に入る前に 一度下がり
戦略を立て直しましょう
Before we enter their range, we should temporarily retreat and construct a new strategy.
There is no need!
（楊端和）その必要はない
Yang Duan He?
楊端和…
騒ぐ… 山の民の血が
It's raging... the blood of the Mountain People.
This way.
（壁）こっちだ
Hey, Brother Bi,
（信）よう 壁のあんちゃん
does this really lead to where Chengjiao is?
本当に
こっから 成蟜がいるとこまで―
行けるんだろうな？
The path from this corridor to the inner palace turns into a complex maze...
この回廊から本殿までの道は
複雑な迷路になっていて―
普通は
通り抜けることなど できない
so one can't normally find their way through it.
（壁）だが 安心しろ
But rest assured.
We broke Lord Piao out of there once before.
我らは
一度 漂どのを脱出させたのだ
I have the path to the inner palace perfectly memorized!
本殿に通ずる道は
全て 頭に入っている
ハハッ… なんだよ
今日の壁のあんちゃんは頼もしいな
Man, you're really reliable today, Brother Bi!
You must be pretty fired up!
気合い入ってんじゃんかよ
Of course I am!
（壁）当たり前だ！
Ever since we broke Lord Piao out of here, there have been many sacrifices.
漂どのを脱出させたときから
ここまで 多くの犠牲が出た
As vice captain, that responsibility is heavier than what I can put into words.
副官として
その責任は 言葉にできぬほど重い
皆の死をムダにせぬためにも―
So that everyone's deaths will not have been in vain, I will risk my life to kill Chengjiao!
私の命を懸けて 成蟜を討つ！
If you're dead, you can't beat Chengjiao!
死んだら成蟜を討てねえぞ！
（昌文君）どうした？ 楊端和どの
下がられよ
What's wrong, Lord Yang Duan He?
Let us retreat!
Against that many arrows, even Mountain People are unable to defend themselves!
あの数の矢は
いかに山の民とて 防ぎようがない
下がるのだ！
We must retreat!
We Mountain People will not yield to things such as arrows!
矢ごときに
屈する我ら山の民ではない！
Prepare to charge!
突撃態勢！
Madness... Stop!
バカな… よせ！
Those monkeys. It seems they truly intend to take on my elite forces.
猿どもめ
この魏興の精鋭部隊を相手に
やる気のようだな
面白い！
Interesting!
All units, get as close as possible to the targets...
全員 ギリギリまで的に接近せよ！
then feed them arrows without a single miss!
一矢(いっし)外さず 食らわせてやれ！
We'll be wiped out!
（昌文君）
全滅するぞ… ひけ 楊端和どの！
Draw back, Lord Yang Duan He!
No. We will continue with the Mountain People!
（政）
いや 俺たちも山の民に続くぞ
My king?!
大王…
All units, fire a volley!
（魏興）全員 一斉射撃！
射(う)てー！
Charge!
突撃！
What?! Those three were alive?!
なんと…
生きておったのか あの３人
おのれ 死に損ないが！
Death-dodging bastards!
何をしている！
前方 一斉射撃だ！
What are you doing?!
Forward group, fire a volley!
（竭氏）な… なんということだ
Wh-What is this?!
Shi Shi! Don't just stand there! Can't you come up with some plan?!
肆氏 突っ立っておらんで
何か策を講じぬか！
Messenger!
伝令！
（伝令）はっ！
Sir!
Gather all of the palace's guards!
王宮中の衛兵を集めよ！
ここで決着をつける
We'll settle this here!
Zuoci
This is all?
これだけか
左慈…
（信）知ってんのか？
Zuoci!
You know him?
He's Shi Shi's right hand... and Jie Shi's chief assassin.
肆氏の片腕にして
竭氏の人斬り長だ
えっ？ 人斬り長？
Chief assassin?
In the conflict between Lu Shi and Jie Shi...
（壁）呂氏(りょし)と竭氏の争いでは―
each camp would continually assassinate the other one's influential men.
それぞれの陣の有力者に対して
暗殺の応酬が続いていた
And the one doing most of the maneuvering behind the scenes for their side was Zuoci.
そこで主に暗躍していたのが左慈だ
私の友人も
何人か ヤツの手にかかっている
Many of my friends also met their end by his hand.
殺し屋ってやつか
So he's a hitman?
安心しな
…んな野郎 俺が斬ってやるぜ
Relax. I'll take care 'a that bastard.
Don't make light of Zuoci!
（壁）左慈を侮るな！
You can see the face of an assassin in his shadow.
暗殺者の顔は
ヤツの影の一面であって―
本性は 生え抜きの武人だ
He's a true-blue warrior.
その左慈が率いる兵も
また手ごわい
And the soldiers he leads are strong as well.
But inside the royal palace,
だが 王宮内には
左慈と魏興のほかに―
besides Zuoci and Weixing,
前線で 兵士たちを
まとめられる者はいない
there's no one who can lead a front of soldiers.
If we get through here,  it'll be a short distance to the inner palace!
ここを突破すれば
本殿までの道のりは近いぞ
ここが正念場だ！
This is the critical moment!
Ya hear that, Captain?!
…だってよ 隊長！
ハアーッ！
Let's kill... them all.
全員 殺す
That's our line!
（兵士Ａ）
それは こっちのセリフだー！
トリャー！
So this is the power of the Mountain People?
（昌文君）これが山の民の力か…
分かっていたつもりであったが
これほどとは…
I thought I understood, but...
to think it was this great...
Lord Yang Duan He, it seems I underestimated your people's power.
楊端和どの
わしは そなたたちの力を
甘く見ていたようだ
It was rude of me to call for retreat.
“下がれ”などと
失礼なことを申した
You have nothing to apologize for.
（楊端和）謝ることはない
そなたの判断も正しかったのだ
Your judgement was correct, as well.
だが…
But...
（楊端和）
我らには我らの戦い方がある！
We have our own way of fighting!
A woman?
（兵士Ａ）女？
（兵士Ｂ）山の王 楊端和は…
The Mountain King, Yang Duan He is...
（兵士Ｃ）女だったのか！
It was a woman?!
If we cut down Yang Duan He, it'll be a big achievement for us!
（兵士Ｄ）
楊端和を討ち取れば 大手柄だ！
We'll get all the rewards and eminence we could want!
（兵士Ｅ）褒美も出世も思いのまま
（兵士Ｆ）
その白い首 切り裂いてやる！
Let's cut off that white head!
１人たりとも敵を生かしておくな！
血祭りだ！
Don't leave a single enemy alive! This is a bloodbath!
トリャー！
ハアーッ！
（斬る音）
（兵士たち）ウワーッ！
Awesome...
（貂）すげえ…
Beyond awesome...
すごすぎる…
Get 'em, guys!
（貂）みんな やっちまえ～！
He's not here.
（戦士Ａ）あいつが いない
どこだ？
Where is he?
（左慈）ここだよ
Right here.
フッ… 次
Next.
You bastards... are too cocky.
調子に乗り過ぎだよ 貴様ら
な… なんということだ
Th-That's insane...
たった ふた振りで
完全に流れが変えられてしまった
In just two swings, he changed the entire flow of the battle.
こ… これが 左慈か！
Th... This is Zuoci?!
クッ… 何をしている…
What am I doing?
今こそ
隊を率いる私がヤツの前に出て
As our leader, now's the most important time...
for me to step out in front of him to boost our morale!
味方の士気を高めるとき
だが 分かっていても 体が動かぬ…
But... even knowing that... my body won't move.
It just won't!
動かぬ！
Hey, hey.
お前(めえ)こそ 調子に乗り過ぎだよ
You're the one who's too cocky!
With that stupid face of yours!
まぬけヅラ！
（壁）信！
Xin!
This presence...
（戦士）
この気配 バジオウですか？
Is it Bajiou?
いや 恐らく あの少年だ
No. Most likely, it's that boy.
あそこでも
本当の戦いが始まりそうだな
The true battle seems to be starting in there.
（信）ハァ…
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
～♪
Preview
（信）
これは 漂から受け継いだ剣だ！
This is the sword I inherited from Piao!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）血は流し尽くした
ここから出せるものは ただひとつ
Now that all the blood has been drained from it,
only one thing can be drawn out!
The Ultimate Blade
End
次回 “究極の一刀”
Next time,